uspa.org 2014-12-16

# U.S. Parachute Association - Skydive Today!

U.S. Parachute Association is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the U.S. Parachute Association Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the U.S. Parachute Association website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

U.S. Parachute Association collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. U.S. Parachute Association also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by U.S. Parachute Association. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by U.S. Parachute Association for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the U.S. Parachute Association Web site.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through U.S. Parachute Association public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: U.S. Parachute Association does not read any of your private online communications.

U.S. Parachute Association encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from U.S. Parachute Association so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. U.S. Parachute Association is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the U.S. Parachute Association and U.S. Parachute Association family of Web sites.

U.S. Parachute Association collects and uses your personal information to operate the U.S. Parachute Association Web site and deliver the services you have requested. U.S. Parachute Association also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from U.S. Parachute Association and its affiliates. U.S. Parachute Association may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

U.S. Parachute Association does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. U.S. Parachute Association may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partner

U.S. Parachute Association is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the U.S. Parachute Association Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the U.S. Parachute Association website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

Collection of your Personal Information

U.S. Parachute Association collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. U.S. Parachute Association also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by U.S. Parachute Association. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by U.S. Parachute Association for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the U.S. Parachute Association Web site.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through U.S. Parachute Association public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: U.S. Parachute Association does not read any of your private online communications.

U.S. Parachute Association encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from U.S. Parachute Association so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. U.S. Parachute Association is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the U.S. Parachute Association and U.S. Parachute Association family of Web sites.

Use of your Personal Information

U.S. Parachute Association collects and uses your personal information to operate the U.S. Parachute Association Web site and deliver the services you have requested. U.S. Parachute Association also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from U.S. Parachute Association and its affiliates. U.S. Parachute Association may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

U.S. Parachute Association does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

U.S. Parachute Association keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within U.S. Parachute Association, in order to determine what U.S. Parachute Association services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within U.S. Parachute Association to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

U.S. Parachute Association Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on U.S. Parachute Association or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of U.S. Parachute Association; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of U.S. Parachute Association, or the public.

Use of Cookies

The U.S. Parachute Association Web site use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize U.S. Parachute Association pages, or register with U.S. Parachute Association site or services, a cookie helps U.S. Parachute Association to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same U.S. Parachute Association Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the U.S. Parachute Association features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the U.S. Parachute Association services or Web sites you visit.

Security of your Personal Information

U.S. Parachute Association secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. U.S. Parachute Association secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

Changes to this Statement

U.S. Parachute Association will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. U.S. Parachute Association encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how U.S. Parachute Association is protecting your information.

Contact Information

U.S. Parachute Association welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that U.S. Parachute Association has not adhered to this Statement, please contact U.S. Parachute Association at [webmaster@uspa.org](mailto:webmaster@uspa.org). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem. 

USPA Privacy Statement

USPA respects the privacy of its members and other visitors to its web site. USPA strongly believes that if electronic commerce and online activities are to flourish, consumers must be assured that information provided online is used responsibly and appropriately. 

What Information Does USPA Collect?

USPA collects only the necessary information to conduct membership transactions, record certain member demographics data for safety and sport promotion purposes and track web site usage.

How Does USPA Use the Data Collected?

USPA may from time to time rent its postal mailing list of members who have not indicated that they wish to be excluded. E-mail addresses are not provided to others, but may be used for USPA internal communications.

Member names, licenses, ratings and membership expiration dates are provided on a limited access database for the exclusive use of Group Member Drop Zones. Addresses are not included.
